Hello and welcome. I'm Charlie.
أهلًا ومرحبًا. أنا تشارلي.
You're going to learn to write Python programs to solve practical problems.
ستتعلمون كتابة برمجة Python لحل المشكلات العملية.
And I'm Phillip. As Charlie said,
وأنا فيليب. وكما قالت شارلي،
you'll be learning about Python but we'll also be
ستتعلمون Python ولكننا أيضًا
demonstrating the skills you need to be an effective programmer.
سنشرح المهارات التي تحتاجون إليها لكي تكون مبرمجًا مؤثرًا.
That's right. There's more to programming than just syntax.
هذا صحيح. هناك الكثير في مجال البرمجة أكثر من مجرد بناء جملة.
For example, programmers need to be able to take an idea and turn it into
على سبيل المثال، يحتاج المترجمون أن يكونوا قادرين على أخذ فكرة وتحويلها إلى كود
code and you'll need to be able to research solutions to novel problems.
وستحتاجون أن تكونوا قادرين على البحث عن حلول جديدة.
First though, we should introduce ourselves better.
أولًا، يجب أن نقدم أنفسنا بطريقة أفضل.
I've been using Python for seven years.
أنا أستخدم Python لأكثر من سبع سنوات.
Mostly as a web developer.
وفي الغالب كمطور ويب.
I've worked on payment portals,
لقد عملت في بوابات الدفع
internationalizations, web scrapers and general back end work.
وبمجال التوطين ومتتبعات الويب وعمل الواجهات الخلفية العامة
Python is also my go to language for solving random problems.
كما أن Python لغتي التي ألجأ إليها لحل المشكلات العشوائية.
Even ones that aren't related to web development.
حتى التي لا ترتبط بمجال تطوير الويب.
Yeah. Python is good for all sorts of things.
نعم. لغة Python مفيدة لكل أنواع الأشياء.
In my previous life, I was a mathematician.
في حياتي السابقة، كنت عالمة رياضيات.
My first big Python project was working on Sage which
كان أول مشروع Python كبير ليّ هو العمل على دالة Sage
is open source mathematical software that I was using for my research.
وهي عبارة عن برنامج رياضيات مفتوح المصدر كنت أستخدمه في بحثي.
It was surprisingly easy to get started on contributing
كان الأمر سهلًا حقًا أن أبدأ في المساهمة في
to Sage and the community taught me a lot.
دالة Sage وتعلمت الكثير من هذا الوسط.
It sounds like we've had pretty different experiences.
يبدو أن لدينا تجارب مختلفة تمامًا.
Here's hoping that this is the start of
هنا نأمل أن تكون هذه البداية
an exciting Python programming career for you. Let's get to it.
لحياة مهنية مثيرة في مجال برمجة Python. والآن لندخل بالموضوع.